Prey For The Hunters
The Ghost and the Darkness is a adventure, thriller,
history film directed by Stephen Hopkins.
Sir Robert Beaumont is behind schedule on a railroad in Africa.
Enlisting noted engineer John Henry Patterson to right
the ship, Beaumont expects results.
Everything seems great until the crew discovers the mutilated corpse
of the project's foreman, seemingly killed by a lion.
After several more attacks, Patterson calls in famed hunter Charles
Remington, who has finally met his match in the bloodthirsty lions.
Charles Remington, played by Michael Douglas.
Col. John Henry Patterson, played by Val Kilmer.
Sir Robert Beaumont, played by Tom Wilkinson.
Samuel, played by John Kani.
Helena Patterson, played by Emily Mortimer.
Dr. David Hawthorne, played by Bernard Hill.
The Ghost and the Darkness is a 1996 American historical adventure film  directed
by Stephen Hopkins and starring Val Kilmer and Michael Douglas.
The screenplay, written by William Goldman, is a fictionalized account of the Tsavo man-eaters, a pair of lions that terrorized
workers in and around Tsavo, Kenya during the building of the Uganda-Mombasa Railway in East Africa in 1898.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $75 million
against a production budget of $55 million.
It won the Academy Award for Best Sound Editing for
supervising sound editor Bruce Stambler.
The film explores themes of london, england, based on
novel or book, hunter, africa, lion.
The tone is intense.